<monster>
    <identity>
        <name>
            <local id="fr">Espion</local>
            <local id="eng">Spy</local>
        </name>
        <size>Medium</size>
        <type>Humanoid</type>
        <typeTags><race>any</race></typeTags>
        <alignment>any</alignment>
        <ac value="12" />
        <hp>6d8</hp>
        <speeds><speed unit="feet" value="30" /></speeds>
    </identity>
    <abilities str="11" dex="15" con="10" int="12" wis="14" cha="16" />
    <skillMisc>
        <skills>
            <skill name="Deception" value="+5"/>
            <skill name="Insight" value="+4"/>
            <skill name="Investigation" value="+5"/>
            <skill name="Perception" value="+6"/>
            <skill name="Persuasion" value="+5"/>
            <skill name="SleightOfHand" value="+4"/>
            <skill name="Stealth" value="+4"/>
        </skills>
        <languages anyLanguage="2" />
        <cr>1</cr>
    </skillMisc>
    <traits>
        <trait>
            <name>
                <local id="fr">Action rusée</local>
                <local id="eng">Cunning Action</local>
            </name>
            <description>
                <local id="fr">À chacun de ses tour, l'espion peut utiliser une action bonus pour faire un Sprint, un Désengagement ou se Cacher.</local>
                <local id="eng">On each of its turns, the spy can use a bonus action to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</local>
            </description>
        </trait>
        <trait>
            <name>
                <local id="fr">Attaque silencieuse (1/Tour)</local>
                <local id="eng">Sneak Attack (1/Turn)</local>
            </name>
            <description>
                <local id="fr">L'esption inflige 7 (2d6) dégâts supplémentaire quand il touche une cible avec une attaque armée et qu'il a l'avantage sur son jet d'attaque, ou lorsque la cible est à moins d'1m50 d'un allié de l'espion capable d'agir et que l'espion n'a pas de désavangate sur son jet d'attaque. </local>
                <local id="eng">The spy deals an extra 7 (2d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack and has advantage on the attack roll, or when the target is  within 5 feet of an ally of the spy that isn't incapacitated and the spy does n't have disadvantage on the attack roll..</local>
            </description>
        </trait>
    </traits>
    <actions>
        <action type="multiattack">
            <local id="fr">L'éclaireur réalise deux attaque de corps à corps.</local>
            <local id="eng"> The scout makes two melee attacks.</local>
        </action>
        <action type="weapon" id="shortsword">
            <hitBonus>+4</hitBonus>
            <damageBonus>+2</damageBonus>
        </action>
        <action type="weapon" id="hand-crossbow">
            <hitBonus>+4</hitBonus>
            <damageBonus>+2</damageBonus>
        </action>
    </actions>
    <description>
        <local id="fr">Régents, nobles, marchands, maîtres de guilde et autre riches individus utilisent des espions pour gagner l'avantage dans un monde de politique sans pitier. Un espion est entrainé à récupérer des informations secrètement. Les espions loyaux préfèreraient mourir que de divulguer des informations pouvant compromettre leur employeur.</local>
        <local id="eng">Rulers, nobles, merchants, guild masters, and other wealthy individuals use spies to gain the upper hand in a world of cutthroat politics. A spy is trained to secretly gather information. Loyal spies would rather die than divulge information that could compromise them or their employers.</local>
    </description>
    <source page="349">MM</source>
    <source>Basic Rules</source>
</monster>
